

danil.miheev2222@gmail.com | 1(206)-710-83-93 | Seattle, WA 98001 | linkedin.com/in/danilaalbutov

Desired Role : Software QA Engineer

Summary:

An Automation Testing Engineer with 4+ years experience in manual and automated testing of websites, mobile apps and software applications. Well known in Front-End and Back-End application testing, thanks to personal experience in development using React, Node.js and other Full-Stack technologies. Adaptable to Agile, SCRUM, and Waterfall methodologies, committed to team success and continuous learning.

Skills:

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, C++, SQL, (XPath, XML, HTML5, CSS3)
- Methodologies: Agile / SCRUM, Waterfall
- Bug Tracking Tools: Jira, Confluence

- Automation Tools: Selenium WebDriver, Selenium IDE, PostmanAPI, Swagger, GTMetrix, BrowserStack, SoapUI, RestAssured, JUnit
- Security Testing Tools: Mozilla Observatory, Snyk
- Source Control: Git, GitHub

Experience:

Carmovers | Seattle, WA **QA Engineer** 02/2023 - Current

- Created and, handling both the Front-End and Back-End for the platform
- Conducted manual and automated testing for web applications, mobile apps, and software products.
- Collaborated with development teams to maintain quality standards throughout the project lifecycle.

WIX, wix.com | Ulyanovsk, WA **Automation QA Engineer** 01/2018 - 01/2022

- Contributed to daily Scrum meetings for improved cross-team communication.
- Conducted Front-End cross-browser testing (Selenium WebDriver, Python UnitTest).
- Executed REST API testing (Postman, JavaScript, Chrome Dev tools, GitHub).
- Performed various testing types: Functional, Ad-Hoc, and UI/UX End-to-End Testing.

Sport Club Torpedo | Ulyanovsk, Russia IT Customer Support Specialist 03/2017 - 06/2018

- Managed customer support, including installation, configuration, troubleshooting, and training as needed.
- Generated detailed reports for management review.
- Resolved a wide range of user issues and directed complex problems to specialized IT teams.

Education and Training:

- Ulyanovsk State University | Bachelor of Mathematics And Computer Science (Incomplete)
- Coursera | Google Automation with Python Professional
- Coursera | Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate
- Coursera | Google IT Support Professional Certificate
- QA Automation Engineer Course At Silicon Valley CA, QASV.US
- TestPro | QA Bootcamp

Personal Projects:

- https://www.carmovers.direct Front-end(Vue3) , Back-end ,php +famework Yii2 + js
- https://danila-albutov.netify.app personal webportfolio on React
- https://pokedex-study-project.netlify.app a web based pokemon encyclopedia
- https://berserkapptodo.netlify.app Planning App in Berserk style
- My github: https://github.com/dankramer2222